Turn on, then come back and tune it in, and then drop out again, and turn on, and tune it back in. It's a rhythm. Now, most of us are brain-damaged by what
Marcia McLuhan would call the Gutenberg galaxy, and most of us think that God and the DNA code made this universe in the nature of subject-object-predicative sentences.
There's no level of energy and no process in biology or physics that operates with subject-predicative sentences. Turn on, tune in, drop out, period, end the paragraph, turn the page. It's all a rhythm. It's all a beat. Jackie, give us the beat.
You turn on, you find it inside, then you have to come back, you can't stay high all the time, and you have to start building a better model, building a better building, building a better temple, building a better poem, building a better language, building a better music.
It's always been done that way, but don't get caught, don't get hooked, don't get attracted by the thing you're building because you got to drop out, and it's a cycle.
Turn on, tune in, drop out, keep it going, keep it going, because the nervous system operates that way.
100,000 million signals a second, right? I'm sorry, 1,000 million signals a second coming into the nervous system. It's that same beat, you got to keep it flowing, you got to keep it flowing.
I want to talk for a minute about the turn, turn on. To turn on, you have to have a keen to get in touch with the neurological sensory and cellular information that you've got stored in that 2 billion-year-old receptacle you call your body.
Now, how do you turn on? Well, I'll tell you this, you can't turn on with words, you can't turn on with thinking, you can't think you way out the sticky black molasses chest board of American education.
I'm sorry, and good works won't do it for you either. You can be as virtuous and as good as you want to, but you're not going to turn on and get the key to the mystery that way.
In order to turn on, you've got to have what the religious metaphor calls a sacrament. What's a sacrament? A sacrament is something that changes your body, that changes your nervous system, and if a sacrament that you use doesn't affect your body, doesn't bring about this internal change, then it's not a sacrament.
It's a television show prop that they're giving you to keep you nice and quiet in the core of the studio.
It staggers the imagination to think of the means and the methods that men have used in the past to turn on, to bring about a change in the sensory, neural equipment that we carry around with.
It's hardly any activity, physical, sensory, or even television prop studio activity that men haven't used in one time or another to get high, to go out of their minds, to come to their senses, to take the trip.
Flagulation, solitude, predicate large temples, silence, music, the Tompura, the Indian beat, the drums in Africa, sexual abstinence,
carefully worked out in systematic routines of tantric sexuality in which you find the divine, with a member of the opposite sex, fasting, or the ingestion of sacred foods.
Not today, the sacrament is a chemical, or it's a series of chemicals.
Now, let's not get upset about LSD. In first place, there are longer, stronger, more powerful chemicals that have the same effect as LSD.
There are in circulation right now in the United States. There'll be many more coming along.
I make this flat prediction, this facet of the government passed the law against one of these molecules, a new one will come along because for thousands of years, Caesar has been trying to stop people from wandering off the stage set of the studio game and getting outside, under the stars, getting back inside to figure out what it's all about.
So, let's not get too upset about LSD because even the era of biochemistry for bringing about the cellular experience is almost over.
Within your lifetime, you will see the new sacrament, or the new key to the internal process developed. In our fact, most of you are going to have a terrible time with your kids in about 25 years, because you'll be sitting around home, smoking marijuana, and preparing for your next weekly LSD session like good news.